{
    "id": "48fdcf2b6950491bbcac45a7d24ed16a",
    "title": "Definite And Indefinite Articles",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "Twelve inches make ………………. foot.",
            "description": "The indefinite article ‘a’ can be used in the numerical sense of one.",
            "answers": [
                "the",
                "a",
                "No article is required"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "bc57fd1cfb5449a8a6b6d7eb591b0f7b"
        },
        {
            "question": "One evening ……………………. beggar came to my door.",
            "description": "The indefinite article ‘a’ can be used in the vague sense of ‘a certain’.",
            "answers": [
                "a",
                "the"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "54dc8db8b95e446986005fdf19f93a99"
        },
        {
            "question": "…………………….. student should obey her teacher.",
            "description": "The indefinite article ‘a’ can be used in the sense of ‘any’.",
            "answers": [
                "A",
                "The",
                "No article is required"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "10d37f58827a4c66adf1cf2e4bf9c4db"
        },
        {
            "question": "At last ……………………….. warrior in him was thoroughly aroused.",
            "description": "The definite article ‘the’ is sometimes placed before a common noun to give it the meaning of an abstract noun.",
            "answers": [
                "a",
                "the",
                "No article is required"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "90e12b8dec5f4a0b9a3b4a1c83541b01"
        },
        {
            "question": "This is ………………………. best book on elementary chemistry.",
            "description": "The definite article ‘the’ is used with superlative adjectives.",
            "answers": [
                "a",
                "the",
                "No article is required"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "96f0b1cdc5fc4fc38ee9abe7294d2c02"
        },
        {
            "question": "What kind of ……………………….. is it?",
            "description": "Articles are omitted before common nouns used in their widest sense.",
            "answers": [
                "flower",
                "the flower",
                "a flower"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "e9a1969fe0af4412bfa0251a6d0620fd"
        },
        {
            "question": "Newton was ……………………….. great scientist and philosopher.",
            "description": "The indefinite article ‘a’ can be used in the numerical sense of ‘one’.",
            "answers": [
                "a",
                "the",
                "No article is required"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "7ef6cc6ce59f44db96b3c92d67e089d4"
        },
        {
            "question": "I cannot forget ……………………….. with which he treated me.",
            "description": "An abstract noun may have the article ‘the’ when it is followed by an adjective or adjectival phrase.",
            "answers": [
                "kindness",
                "a kindness",
                "the kindness"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "f5ac4215307e4b3885815914beb9cd83"
        },
        {
            "question": "……………………… is the only animal that uses fire.",
            "description": "When the noun man is used in the general sense, it does not take an article.",
            "answers": [
                "Man",
                "The man",
                "A man"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "6e4dae23d075480c885ec5cb7fc4b6aa"
        },
        {
            "question": "……………………. tenth chapter of this book is very interesting.",
            "description": "The definite article ‘the’ is used with ordinal numbers.",
            "answers": [
                "The",
                "A",
                "No article is required"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "4609e005f5684b32b18fd20e7b73d223"
        },
        {
            "question": "……………………….. is its own reward.",
            "description": "Articles are omitted before abstract nouns used in a general sense.",
            "answers": [
                "Virtue",
                "A virtue",
                "The virtue"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "38ce1105de3b47f992e409c8e226ab25"
        },
        {
            "question": "I learnt German at ……………………..",
            "description": "No article is used when the reference is to the primary purpose of the nouns school, college, hospital, prison or church.",
            "answers": [
                "school",
                "a school",
                "the school"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "6aa56a94644945c5a9c6ee448286f0a3"
        }
    ]
}